A Guide to the Clarence M. Connelly papers, Rockefeller Univeristy Faculty FA153
Rockefeller Archive Center
Clarence M. Connelly papers, Rockefeller University Faculty
1939-1967
Rockefeller Archive Center
Rockefeller University
Rockefeller Institute for Medical Research
Connelly, Clarence M.
FA153
1.3 Cubic Feet 1 record storage box
Biographical/Historical note
Clarence M. Connelly (1916- ), physicist and Dean of Graduate Studies, was a member of The Rockefeller University faculty from 1954 until his retirement on December 31, 1984.
Connelly received his A.B. from Cornell University in 1938 and continued graduate studies there until 1942. From 1942-1946 he was a staff member with the Radiation Lab of M.I.T. where he worked on radar development. He joined Deltev Bronk's research group in 1946 at the Johnson Research Foundation of the University of Pennsylvania as an American Cancer Society pre doctoral fellow, where, in 1949, he received his Ph. D in biophysics. Connelly's work in biophysics focused on nerve cell function and activity.
From 1949-1954 Connelly was an assistant professor at John's Hopkins University.
While at The Rockefeller University, he become Associate Dean of Graduate Students In 1962 and assumed the responsibilities of full Dean in 1980. In this capacity he worked with members of the faculty and the V. P. for Academic Programs in a effort to locate and attract prospective students.
Scope and Contents note
Consists of lab notebooks.
File Plan note
Former Classification: I 450 C762
Conditions Governing Access note
Access to this collection is restricted pending permission from Rockefeller University.
Arrangement
As received.
Physics; Biophysics
- Lab Notebook, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Lab Notebook, 1947-1948 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Lab Notebook - Voltage Clamp, 1958-1959, 1965, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Lab Notebook - Journal - Johnson Foundation, 1947 February-1948 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Lab Notebook - Johnson Foundation - Early Oxygen Consumption of Limulus (some frog), 1946 Fall-1947 June (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Lab Notebook, Notes, 1939-1948 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Lab Notebook 3, 1950 September 25-1951 November (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Lab Notebook 4, 1951 November 27-1952 May 23 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Lab Notebook 6, 1952 November 21-1953 January 20 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Lab Notebook 7, 1953 January 20-1954 March 12 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Ledger, "Record", 1949 March 14-1952 (Box 1, Folder 11)